Guide to the Janet G. Travell papers, 1910-1997 MS0704.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Galley proofs and manuscript drafts of Dr. Travell's books, 1915-1994; MS0704 Series 6; 6.5 Linear feet (Box 90, Box 91, Box 88, Box 89, Box 86, Box 87, Box 84, Box 85, Box 97, Box 96, Box 95, Box 94, Box 93, Box 92)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons, 1990 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons, 1990 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Table of Contents, Chapter 1, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 2, Chapter 4, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 13, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 15, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 19, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 20, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 21, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 22, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 23, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 27, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 27, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Chapter 28, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and illustrations for second volume of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons - Appendices, 1991 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and sketches for second edition of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons, 1984-1987 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs and sketches for second edition of Myofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, co-authored by David Simons, 1984-1987 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs for Dr. Travell's autobiography Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968 ca. (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs for Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968 ca. (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs for Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968 ca. (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley proofs of Office Hours: Day and Night for McCall's magazine excerpt, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: General correspondence with the editor of Dr. Travell's autobiography Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    See also Series IV Miscellaneous Correspondence 1966-1967
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: List of illustrations and captions for Dr. Travell's autobiography, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: List of individuals who could provide comments and reviews for Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript draft for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 1, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Dr. Travell's autobiography Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 1, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 2, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 3, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 4, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 5, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 6, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 7, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 8, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 9, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 10, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapters 10-12, 1967 ca. (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 11, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 12, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 13, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 14, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 15, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 16, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 17, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 18, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 19, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 20, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 21, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 22, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 23, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 23, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 14)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript drafts for Office Hours: Day and Night Index, 1967 ca. (Box 95, Folder 15)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscript on Pain Relief for Sprains, 1947 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Manuscripts on Orthopaedics, 1956 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Nashville Autograph Party for book tour, 12/02/1968 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: New York radio and Television appearances to promote Dr. Travell's autobiography, 01/08/1969 -01/13/1969 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Newspaper Clippings about Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Dr. Travell's autobiography Office Hours: Day and Night - Preface and Table of Contents, 1960-1968 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Barry Goldwater, 1961-1964 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 2, 1966 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 3, 1910-1967 ca. (Box 96, Folder 9)
    Including letters to her father when she was a child and some written by her mother, plus "Baby Book"
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 4, 1966 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 5, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 6, 1915-1966 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    Including homework as a girl and report cards
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 7, 1935-1966 (Box 96, Folder 13)
    Including letters from her father and articles he wrote
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Dr. Travell's autobiography Office Hours: Day and Night (published 1968) - Chapter 9, 1929-1967 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 10, 1961-1967 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 11, 1933-1967 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 11, 1929-1967 (Box 96, Folder 17)
    Including clipping from her wedding
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 12, 1933-1967 (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 13, 1949-1967 (Box 96, Folder 19)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 14, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 20)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 15, 1967 (Box 96, Folder 21)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 16, 1958-1967 (Box 96, Folder 22)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 17, 1960-1969 (Box 96, Folder 23)
    Including Inaugural Program, 1961
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Dr. Travell's autobiography Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 18, 1960-1967 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 19, 1961-1967 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 21, 1963-1967 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 23, 1964 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - Chapter 23, 1961-1968 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - LBJ Ranch, 1964-1965 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes and correspondence for Office Hours: Day and Night - sister Virginia Travell Weeks,M.D., 1922-1961 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Notes for book outline, 1948-1958 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Photographs used in Dr. Travell's autobiography, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Publicity for Office Hours: Day and Night, 1966-1969 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Reviews of Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968-1969 (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Table of contents for Dr. Travell's book Management of Skeletal Pain (MacMillan), 1960ca. (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Galley Proofs and Manuscript Drafts: Travell autobiography as a "Talking Book", 1971 -1972 (Box 97, Folder 13)
- Personal papers, books, and certificates, 1926-1996; MS0704 Series 7; 6.5 Linear feet (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105)
  This series contains personal items of Dr, Travell's such as appointment and expense books, certificates, passports, photographs, correspondence relating to her Wellesley years, books, videocassettes based on her Trigger Point Manual, framed photographs, plaques, and artifacts such as her lab coat and jump ropes. The series dates from 1926-96, with the bulk of material ranging from 1958-85.
  - Personal Papers: 50th Anniversary Reunion of John Powell's class at University of North Carolina, 05/31/1969 -06/02/1969 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - Personal Papers: Abstracts of Janet G. Travell Papers, 1976 (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - Personal Papers: American Academy of Pain Management Janet Travell Soft Tissue Award to David Simons, 09/15/1990 (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - Personal Papers: American Academy of Pain Management Janet Travell Soft Tissue Award to Lawrence Funt, 08/31/1991 (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - Personal Papers: American Academy of Pain Management Janet Travell Soft Tissue Award to Anders Sola, 10/10/1992 (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Personal Papers: Appointment/Day book, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Personal Papers: Appointment/Day book, 1974 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Personal Papers: Appointment/Day book, 1977 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers: Autobiographical sketches from Janet Travell, and bibliographies, 1966-1984 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Personal Papers: Betty Hughes Program, WCAU-TV, Philadelphia, 04/14/1971 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Personal Papers: Biography of Willard Travell prepared for The National Encyclopedia of America, 1966 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Personal Papers: Certificates, 1979-1996 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Personal Papers: Cornell University Medical Center Office of Women in Medicine - ceremony for Dr. Travell's portrait, New York Hospital, 05/13/1988 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Personal Papers: Doctors using Dr. Travell's treatments, 1965-1968 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Personal Papers: Dr. Travell radio talk show, 07/1960 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Personal Papers: Edmund Muskie Presidential campaign, 1971-1972 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Personal Papers: Expense book, 1949-1972 (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Personal Papers: Expenses, 1960-1961 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Personal Papers: George Washington University Alumni Luncheon, (Lawrence Lamb), 11/14/1966 (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - Personal Papers: George Washington University Emeritus Award, 05/31/1970 (Box 98, Folder 15)
  - Personal Papers: George Washington University luncheon for Lawrence Lamb, 11/14/1966 (Box 98, Folder 16)
  - Personal Papers: George Washington University Women's Board, 1963-1968 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Personal Papers: Grand Rounds - Capitol Hill Hospital, Washington, DC, 12/09/1981 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Personal Papers: Grand Rounds - Doctor's Hospital, Washington, DC, 01/26/1973 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers: Greater Washington Area Hadassah book talk, 10/21/1969 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Personal Papers: Hahnemann University (Philadelphia) - Honorary D.Science. Degree, 06/09/1983 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Personal Papers: Hawaii Trip, 1960 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Personal Papers: Hospital for Special Surgery, 1958 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Personal Papers: Hubert Humphrey Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Personal Papers: International Journal of Myofascial Medicine, 1988-1990 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Personal Papers: Jacobson, Max, M.D., "Dr. Feelgood", 1972 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Personal Papers: Janet Travell Clippings and radio talks, 1944-1957 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Personal Papers: Lawrence Funt's celebration of Dr. Travell's 90th birthday, 12/15/1991 (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Personal Papers: Lyndon Johnson Library dedication, University of Texas-Austin, 05/22/1971 (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Personal Papers: Macmillan book project, 1959 (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Personal Papers: Membership rosters for American Academy of Orofacial Pain (1994) and American Academy of Craniomandibular Disorders (1991), 1991-1994 (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Personal Papers: Nags Head Trip, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Personal Papers: National Rehabilitation Hospital Staff Washington, DC, 02/28/1992 (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - Personal Papers: New York Book and Author luncheon, NY, NY, 02/19/1969 (Box 99, Folder 18)
  - Personal Papers: Notes of John Powell (Dr. Travell's husband) on his marriage to her, 1960-1971 (Box 99, Folder 19)
  - Personal Papers: Notes on Arthur Schlesinger's 1000 Days, 1965 (Box 99, Folder 20)
  - Personal Papers: Notes on Theodore Sorenson's Kennedy, 1965-1970 (Box 99, Folder 21)
  - Personal Papers: Paid Bills, 1965 (Box 99, Folder 22)
  - Personal Papers: Passports of Janet Travell and John Powell, 1926-1972 (Box 99, Folder 23)
  - Personal Papers: Photographs - personal and professional portraits and snapshots with family and colleagues, 1926-1990 - -ca. (Box 99, Folder 24)
  - Personal Papers: Photographs of Dr. Travell examining a patient, 1979 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Personal Papers: Photographs of Dr. Travell examining a patient, 1979 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Personal Papers: Physician's Recognition Award in Continuing Medical Education, 1974-1983 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers: Poems by Janet Travell, 1954-1969 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Personal Papers: Powell, John W.G. (Dr. Travell's husband) - medical records, 1945-1951 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Personal Papers: Power of a Woman Inc, 1972 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Personal Papers: Professional Appointments, 1942-1960 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Personal Papers: Professional Engagements of Janet G. Travell, 1974-1984 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Personal Papers: Scholarship Fund - Lois Alward Raphael, 1960-1967 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Personal Papers: Security clearance papers, 1952-1964 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Personal Papers: St. Albans Tennis Club, 1968-1972 (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Personal Papers: Stocks, bonds, insurance reference binder, 1930-1972 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Personal Papers: "Talking Books" catalog, 1972-1973 (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - Personal Papers: Thermography, George Washington University grant, 1966-1970 (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Personal Papers: Today's Family Doctor magazine cartoon strip by Dr. Travell, 1953 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Personal Papers: Travell, Janet - medical records, 1929-1957 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    Includes 1 x-ray
  - Personal Papers: Travell, Janet - medical records, 1961-1974 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers: Virginia Graham's "Girl Talk" program, 01/3/1970 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Personal Papers: Washington Club talk, 02/05/1969 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Personal Papers: Wellesley Alumnae Reunion Weekend, 06/02/1967 -06/05/1967 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Personal Papers: Wellesley Class Reunion, 06/11/1982 -06/14/1982 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Personal Papers: Wellesley College years- correspondence, examination books, copy of transcript, 1918-1922 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Personal Papers: Who's Who in America, 1965-1966 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Personal Papers: Woman's Medical College of Pennsylvania Awards Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Personal Papers: Women's Board George Washington University, Luncheon Speech -, 06/01/1966 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Personal Papers: Woman's Medical College of Pennsylvania Award, 1966-1969 (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - Personal Papers: Woman's Medical College Pennsylvania Award, 1961-1966 (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Personal Papers: Woman's Medical College Pennsylvania Award, 1970 (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - Personal Papers: Woodward and Lothrop Book Breakfast, 01/15/1969 (Box 101, Folder 15)
  - Videotapes: Introduction to Myofascial Pain Therapy, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    Tape 1 of Myofascial Pain Syndromes: The Travell Trigger Point Tapes
  - Videotapes: Myofascial Pain Syndromes of the Head, Face, Neck, and Shoulder Girdle, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    Tape 2 of Myofascial Pain Syndromes: The Travell Trigger Point Tapes
  - Videotapes: Myofascial Pain Syndromes of the Upper Torso and Shoulder, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    Tape 3 of Myofascial Pain Syndromes: The Travell Trigger Point Tapes
  - Videotapes: Myofascial Pain Syndromes of the Shoulder and Arm, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    Tape 4 of Myofascial Pain Syndromes: The Travell Trigger Point Tapes
  - Videotapes: Myofascial Pain Syndromes of the Low Back and Hips, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    Tape 5 of Myofascial Pain Syndromes: The Travell Trigger Point Tapes
  - Videotapes: Myofascial Pain Syndromes of the Hip, Thigh, and Calf, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    Tape 6 of Myofascial Pain Syndromes: The Travell Trigger Point Tapes
  - Videotapes: Dudley J. Morton's Foot Configuration, undated (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Books: The Merck Manual, 1961 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    (10th edition) Janet Travell's White House copy
  - Books: U.S. Government Organization Manual, 1962-1963 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    by National Archives and Records Service
  - Books: Farewell to Model T, 1936 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    by Lee Strout White
  - Books: Directory of the American College of Clinical Pharmacology and Chemotherapy 1965-66, 1966 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Books: Directory: Alumni Cornell University Medical College 1899-1970 and House Staff The New York Hospital 1913-1970, 1971 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Books: University of the State of New York Bulletin: Registered Physicians 1961-1962 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Books: American Medical Women's Association Directory, 1961 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Books: Social Register, 1993 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    Janet Travell listed on p.623
  - Books: The Social List of Washington, DC, 1996 (Box 103, Folder 9)
    by Thomas J. Murray [Janet Travell listed on p.277]
  - Books: Mysofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, 1992 (Box 103, Folder 10)
    by Janet Travell and David Simons (Lower half of body; Volume 2)